Yen-Yu Chang

736 Serra St, Apt 900, Stanford, CA, 94305, United States of America

□ (650) 407-7300 | ■ yenyu@stanford.edu | ★ yuyuchang.github.io | Im yenyuchang I S rubb9diaw

Research Interests

Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Graph Mining

My research interests lie in the general area of machine learning, particularly in deep learning, time series analysis graph mining, and dynamic graph representation learning, as well as their applications in social network analysis, anomaly detection, knowledge graphs, textual semantic analysis, and multi-agent systems.

Education

Stanford University

Sen 2019 - Present

MASTER OF SCIENCE

Stanford, California

· Major: Electrical Engineering

National Taiwan University (NTU)

Sen 2014 - Jun 2018

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ENGINEERING · Major: Electrical Engineering

Taipei, Taiwan

Cumulative GPA: 3.86/4.00, Major GPA: 3.87/4.00, CS-Related GPA: 3.95/4.00

Publications _

Inductive Representation Learning in Temporal Networks via Causal Anonymous Walks | Link

Yanbang Wang, Yen-Yu Chang, Yunyu Liu, Pan Li, and Jure Leskovec

May. 2021 Virtual

PUBLISHED IN THE 9'TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON LEARNING REPRESENTATIONS (ICLR 2021)

• Proposed Causal Anonymous Walks (CAWs) to inductively represent a temporal network.

- CAW-N is evaluated to predict links over 6 real temporal networks and uniformly outperforms previous SOTA methods by averaged 15% AUC gain in the inductive setting.
- CAW-N also outperforms previous methods in 5 out of the 6 networks in the transductive setting.

F-FADE: Frequency Factorization for Anomaly Detection in Edge Streams | Link

Mar 2021

Yen-Yu Chang, Pan Li, Rok Sosic, Mohamed Ibrahim, Marco Schweighauser, and Jure Leskovec

PUBLISHED IN THE 14'TH ACM INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON WEB SEARCH AND DATA MINING (WSDM-2021)

• Proposed F-FADE that is an purely unsupervised and online approach to detect anomalies in edge streams.

Virtual

- F-FADE provides false-positive-rate guarantees in the detection of single or the group of anomalous edges.
- · Our experiments on one synthetic and six real-world dynamic networks show that F-FADE achieves state of the art performance and may detect anomalies that previous methods are unable to find.

A Regulation Enforcement Solution for Multi-agent Reinforcement Learning | Link

Mav. 2019

Fan-Yun Sun, Yen-Yu Chang, Yueh-Hua Wu, and Shou-De Lin

PUBLISHED IN 2019 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON AUTONOMOUS AGENTS AND MULTIAGENT SYSTEMS (AAMAS-19)

Montreal, Canada

- Proposed the task of Regulation Enforcement and provided its connection to a well known problem (social dilemma).
- Designed a mechanism that discourages the agents from not obeying the global regulation given a decentralized environment.

Designing Non-greedy Reinforcement Learning Agents with Diminishing Reward Shaping | Link

Feb. 2018

Fan-Yun Sun, Yen-Yu Chang, Yueh-Hua Wu, and Shou-De Lin

PUBLISHED IN 2018 AAAI/ACM CONFERENCE ON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE, ETHICS, AND SOCIETY (AIES-18)

New Orleans, USA

- Proposed a cost-effective method to train non-greedy reinforcement learning (RL) agents.
- Conducted multi-agent RL simulations to prove that our method achieved non-homogeneous equality.

ANS: Adaptive Network Scaling for Deep Rectifier Reinforcement Learning Models | Link

Yueh-Hua Wu, Fan-Yun Sun, Yen-Yu Chang, and Shou-De Lin

PREPRINT

- · Provided a thorough study on how reward scaling can affect performance of deep reinforcement learning agents.
- Proposed an Adaptive Network Scaling framework to find a suitable scale of the rewards during learning for better performance.

A Memory-Network Based for Multivariate Time-Series Forecasting | Link

Yen-Yu Chang, Fan-Yun Sun, Yueh-Hua Wu, and Shou-De Lin

- Proposed a memory network-based model for time series prediction with interpretable attention mechanism.
- · Outperform state-of-the-art models in both univariate and multivariate time series forecasting.

Heterogeneous Star Celebrity Games | Link

Yen-Yu Chang, Chin-Chia Hsu, and Ho-Lin Chen

• Proved the Price of Anarchy (i.e., PoA) is upper bounded by $O(\frac{n}{\beta})$ for all Heterogeneous Star Celebrity Games.

FEBRUARY 17, 2021 YEN-YU CHANG · RÉSUMÉ

Research Experiences

Research Assistant, instructed by Prof. Jure Leskovec & Prof. Pan Li

STANFORD NETWORK ANALYSIS PROJECT (SNAP)

Jul. 2019 - Present Stanford, California

 Researched on dynamic graph representation learning, with focus on node classification and link prediction and submitted the paper "Inductive Representation Learning in Temporal Networks via Causal Anonymous Walks" to ICLR-21

Researched on data mining and social network analysis, with focus on anomaly detection and published the paper "F-FADE: Frequency Factorization for Anomaly Detection in Edge Streams" to WSDM-21.

Undergraduate Researcher, instructed by Prof. Hung-Yi Lee & Prof. Lin-Shan Lee

Feb. 2017 - Jun. 2018

SPEECH PROCESSING AND MACHINE LEARNING LABORATORY, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING, NTU

Taipei, Taiwan

· Researched on natural language processing, with focus on visual question answering.

Undergraduate Researcher, instructed by Prof. Shou-de Lin

Jul. 2016 - Jun. 2018

MACHINE DISCOVERY AND SOCIAL NETWORK MINING LABORATORY, DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND INFORMATION ENGINEERING, NTU

Taipei, Taiwan

Researched on reinforcement learning and multi-agent system, with focus on collaborative and ethics behaviors and published the
paper "Designing Non-greedy Reinforcement Learning Agents with Diminishing Reward Shaping" to AIES-19.

 Researched on time series forecasting, with focus on long-term multivariate prediction and preprint the paper "A Memory-Network Based Solution for Multivariate Time-Series Forecasting".

Researched on reinforcement learning and multi-agent system, with focus on learning agent-to-agent interaction and published the
paper "A Regulation Enforcement Solution for Multi-agent Reinforcement Learning" as the extended abstract to AAMAS 2019.

• Participated in KDD Cup 2018 and achieved 19th place in main prize and 4th place in special prize.

Undergraduate Researcher, instructed by Prof. Ho-Lin Chen

Jul. 2015 - Jul. 2017 Taipei, Taiwan

GAME THEORY AND MOLECULAR COMPUTING LABORATORY, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING, NTU

• Researched on game theory, with focus on network creation games and price of anarchy (PoA).

• Proved the upper bound of PoA for all Heterogeneous Star Celebrity Games.

Honors & Awards _____

INTERNATIONAL

2018 19th Place (out of 4180 teams), KDD Cup 2018

London, U.K.

2018 4th Place (out of 4180 teams), KDD Cup 2018 Special Prize

London, U.K.

DOMESTIC

2016 **Dean's List**, GPA in top 5% in Department of Electrical Engineering, NTU

Taipei, Taiwan

Selected Projects _____

Dynamic Graph networks for anomalous behavior detection in social network system

Sep. 2019 - Present

FOR STANFORD NETWORK ANALYSIS PROJECT

- Design new dynamic graph network to model higher-order dependencies between nodes
- Analyze anomalous behaviors in social network systems

Long-term Air Quality Forecasting

Mar. 2018 - Jun. 2018

FOR CSIE7433 (MACHINE LEARNING: THEORY AND PRACTICE)

- · Built a recurrent neural network model to forecast air quality in future 48 hours and applied forecast weather data in our RNN.
- 19th place in KDD Cup 2018 and 4th place in KDD Cup 2018 special prize

Cyber Security Attack Defender

Sep. 2016 - Jan. 2017

FOR EE5177 (MACHINE LEARNING)

- Predict cyber attack based on real world dataset about connection information
- Won **4th prize** in EE5177 final project competition.

Relevant Courses

ML/A

Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition, Mining Massive Data Sets,

Signal Processing for Machine Learning

Mathematics Linear Algebra and Matrix Theory, Convex Optimization

Skills __

Languages Python, C/C++, Shell scripting, Matlab

Libraries/Tools Keras, Tensorflow, Pytorch

OS GNU/Linux (Ubuntu & Arch Linux), Mac OSX

Other Git, LTFX

FEBRUARY 17, 2021 YEN-YU CHANG · RÉSUMÉ